<!-- alert-block -->
<section>

  <md>
    # Alerts

    An alert is a 'standout' block that should be used to provide users with information.

    ## When to Use Alerts

    - To confirm that an action has been completed
    - To warn the user of an error or mistake
    - To provide contextual information, for example, that a number of items are selected

    ## When Not to Use Alerts

    - To display an interface that is not a 'message' to the user
    - To force actions on a user (for example, confirming an action). For this, use a modal instead.
    - To display a lot of content, or provide a very long message. Alerts should only contain small snippets  of information. Consider another layout.

    ## Position and Style

    Alerts can be positioned anywhere in the interface, although ideally, they should be directly against   the page background.

    At most they should be nested one level deep inside a card or other container.

    Do not nest an alert inside another nested block. Never nest alerts inside other alerts.

    The tone of the alert's message can be controlled by using different colors.

    For example, a warning could be shown with either an orange (warning) or red (danger) alert,depending   n the severity.

    If you choose to do this, make sure you also include an icon for colorblind users.

    Alerts can optionally contain a close button so that users can dismiss the message.

    They can also include action buttons (for example, an 'undo' button), although only for actions that the  user can safely ignore.
  </md>

</section>

<section type="example">

  <title>Alert:</title>

  <subtitle>
    <code>.alert</code>
  </subtitle>

  <description>
    A standard alert.
    <br>
    The first element placed inside it will have it's top margin removed.
  </description>

  <example>
    <hbs name="alert">
      <div class="alert">
        <h4>Alert Title</h4>
        <p>Alert content with <a href="#">a link</a>.</p>
        <a class="button top-margin top-margin--small">And a button!</a>
      </div>
    </hbs>

    <!-- alert-component -->
      {{> alert}}
    <!-- alert-component -->
  </example>

</section>

<section>

  <md>
    ### Methods

    #### Open
    `$(element).alert('open', options)`

    ```
    options = {
      isAutoclose: false, // boolean, optional
      delay: 2 // integer, unit in seconds, optional
    }
    ```
    Open the alert and optionally autocloses it.

    #### Close
    `$(element).alert('close')`
    Close the alert.

    #### Toggle
    `$(element).alert('toggle')`
    Toggle the alert.

    #### Remove

    `$(element).alert('remove')`
    Hides then removes an alert.

    ### Accessors

    #### isOpened
    `$(element).alert('isOpened')`
    Return true if the alert is opened, else false.

    #### isClosed
    `$(element).alert('isClosed')`
    Return true if the alert is closed, else false.

    ### Events

    | Event | Triggered by | Occurence |
    |-------|--------------|-----------|
    | open.pdui.alert | open | before |
    | opened.pdui.alert | open | after |
    | close.pdui.alert | close | before |
    | closed.pdui.alert | close | after |
    | toggle.pdui.alert | toggle | before |
    | toggled.pdui.alert | toggle | after |
    | remove.pdui.alert | remove | before |
  </md>

</section>
<!-- alert-block -->